Contact

508-410-6115 (Mobile) naraharipranav@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ pranavnarahari (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Vercel Next.js

Component Library

Certifications

Blockchain Expert

Pranav Narahari

Fullstack Engineer | React + Blockchain enthusiast Austin, Texas, United States

Summary

Software engineer with a unique blend of technical expertise and entrepreneurial drive, primed for startup environments. Hands-on experience designing, developing, implementing, and enhancing features and components for diverse applications. Introduce improvements and solutions to drive application performance/ usability while simplifying internal processes by applying skills in a variety of programming/scripting languages, tools, operating systems, and emerging technologies.

Experience

Selfient
Software Engineer
July 2024 - Present (4 months)

Outlier

Al Technical Training Specialist April 2024 - Present (7 months) Austin, Texas Metropolitan Area

Developing and programming prompt-related solutions, assessing Al responses, and evaluating colleagues' prompts. Enhance NLP accuracy, ensuring high-quality conversational agent performance

License Logic Frontend Engineer March 2024 - March 2024 (1 month) Austin, Texas Metropolitan Area

Led team in the final stage of development to secure first paying customer and revamped entire web tool (2100+ lines of code changed). Eliminated bugs, improved user interface (UI) and user experience (UX), and enhanced functionality.

Citizens
Software Engineer, Cloud

June 2021 - February 2024 (2 years 9 months)

Austin, Texas, United States

During a substantial digital transformation (migration of hundreds of applications from on-prem to the cloud) and I was tasked with automating this process. The company was also looking to update its internal cloud training tools.

Owned internal on-prem to cloud migration service and was the sole developer for cloud training API.

Employed ReactJS to quickly spin up UIs per internal application team specs, using Nunjucks and YAML for templating, utilized Typescript for data processing + API integration, and leveraged AWS Lambda, AWS Layers, and Python for backend development

Drove time to migration down from 3 weeks to 30 mins with our automation. Cloud training tools enhancements: automated creation of a web IDE, email reminders, and programmatic AWS EC2 deletion

Mathematica

Frontend Software Engineer May 2020 - August 2020 (4 months)

Chicago, Illinois, United States

Launched the redesign of app navigation for major devices and dynamically readjust based on the browser size.

Utilized Vue.js for the app framework, Tailwind CSS for consistency and optimization in page styling, HTML for the restructuring of the navigation menu, TypeScript to add dynamic functionality, and GitHub for version control Presented a fully function UI fulfilling requirements of the customer, including low latency, intuitive customer experience, and industry-standard code practices

Kenway Consulting
Backend Engineer and Data Analyst
January 2020 - May 2020 (5 months)
Chicago, IL

While rapidly growing, the firm sought reorganization of its technical architecture and re-evaluation of its tech stack

Led reorganization of the company's data systems, redesigned data processing code, and tested and validated code changes

Enhanced MS SQL Server efficiency by improving in all SQL query selectors and clauses to retrieve and modify data, developed server code in C#, and tested and validated with unit tests and manual test plans

Eliminated data conflicts and consolidated all tables involving internal data, refactored server code to map data to new databases, and maximized code coverage with various forms of testing

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign Computer Science Course Assistant August 2018 - December 2018 (5 months)

Urbana-Champaign, Illinois Area

My responsibilities:

- Provided tutoring in Java to both beginner and intermediate programmers at the University of Illinois and held office hours for 5 hours a week throughout the semester and gave additional assistance at the end of the semester for the android app development final project
- Developed a strong foundation in Java and increased my android app development knowledge

Kumon North America, Inc.

Tutor

October 2013 - August 2017 (3 years 11 months)

Worcester, Massachusetts

My responsibilities were to teach kids from age 4 to 17 basic and complex mathematics and reading topics and techniques, assess students math and reading skills and decide which subject (s)he should begin learning, and data entry of students' performance.

Russian School of Mathematics
Mathematics Tutor
December 2015 - January 2017 (1 year 2 months)
Shrewsbury, Massachusetts

My responsibilities were to assist struggling students with their coursework and assist professors in teaching in classrooms.

Education

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign
Bachelor's degree, Computer Science + Economics · (August 2017 - May 2021)

Massachusetts Academy of Math and Science at WPI

· (August 2015 - May 2017)